本片字幕根据*韩剧天地精品影视* http://hjtd.5d6d.com/
*鬼马小精灵*的版本由PrettySnail修改！
片名：糖果
欢迎高手修正！更多精彩电影，尽在
*韩剧天地精品影视* http://hjtd.5d6d.com/
当我初次遇见凯蒂
When I first met Candy
时光如果汁般甜美
Those were like the days of juice..
一切都变得丰富多彩
Everything was bountiful...
鸟儿在天空翱翔
Birds filled the sky ...
一股暖流在我们之间流淌
a great kindness float through us...
天堂
Heaven
给你!
Here it is.
这次我用你的办法试试
I'm gonna try it your way this time.
坦白说，这办法不错
This is just as good this way. Honestly.
Then why don't you do it?
那你怎么还不动手
舒曼，为什么我不动手
Schumann, Why don't I do it?
凯蒂，丹只是跟班，不是老大
Dan is a follower, Candy. Not a leader.
简单点儿，一直用鼻子吸
We stick to snorting, keep it simple.
有时候，你要敢于尝试不同！
You know...Dare to be different!
我认为我应该去浴盆试试
Well I think I'd like to try it in the bath.
这就是不同
well that's different.
凯蒂
Candy?
Candy!
舒曼，快来帮我！
Schumann, fucking help me!
怎么了
What??
快来
Come here!
快来！宝贝？
Come here!Babe?
噢，天哪
Oh, Christ!
该死，她摄入过量了
Shit, I think that she took too much.
宝贝
Babe!
快给我些生理盐水或者别的什么东西,我需要生理盐水
Fucking saline solution or something?I need saline solution!
什么？
What?
我操！赶紧拿杯水来！
Fuck it!Go and get a glass of water...
放盐进去，快！
Put salt in it! Hurry up!
醒醒，宝贝
Come on!Babe!
凯蒂，看着我！
Candy! Look at me!
放多少盐？
How much salt?
我不知道！看着放吧
I don't know! HEAPS!
快他妈搅啊，确保充分溶解
Just fucking stir it! Make sure it's dissolved!
快来！噢，宝贝！FUCK!
Come here!Oh baby？Fuck!!
哥们儿，这有屁用！盐能干啥！
I don't think this works man!What the fuck's salt gonna do?
闭嘴！
Shut up!
操！扶着她的胳膊
Fuck!Hold her arm!
你他妈扶着她的胳膊！
Hold her fucking arm, man!
用力！
Harder!
这不会...(管用的)
This will not be ...
开始吧
Here we go ...
不，它完全不起作用，狗屎！
No, it's not gonna fucking work!It's bullshit!!
闭上你的乌鸦嘴
Shut up!
叫救护车
Call an ambulance.
我们走
Here we go.
凯蒂，看着我
Candy, look at me.
凯蒂！凯蒂！
Candy! Candy!
凯蒂，看着我！
Candy, Look at me!
宝贝
Babe ...
带她回来
Bring her back.
...回来
...back.
我他妈已经放了不少盐了
Enough with the fucking salt.
感觉很美妙
It was beautiful.
我有点紧张
Intense.
未来飘忽不定
The future or the thing that gleamed.
当下如此美妙
The present was so very, very good.
我从没想过毁去凯蒂的生命
I wasn't trying to wreck Candy's life
我努力使自己变得更好
I was trying to make mine better.
我们渴望分享所有一切
We wanted to share absolutely everything.
尤其是最好的
Especially the best bits .
我要永远和你在一起
I want to stay with you forever.
谁不想呢？
...and who would'nt!
画的是我俩！
It's us!
我称之为
It's called "The afternoon of extravagant delight. "
“狂欢的午后”
By Candy Wyatt.
太美了
It's beautiful.
我喜欢这种感觉
I love it!
卡斯珀
Casper.
卡斯珀，是丹啊
Casper, It's Dan.
丹尼尔，等等，我即将带着胜利和祈祷而来
Daniel, hang on!, I'm coming in on a win and a prayer!
什么？
What?
我正试着在迪拜降落
I'm trying to land a Jumbo in Dubai.
你秀逗了？
What?
卡斯珀就像你一直想要的父亲
Casper was like the dad you always wanted.
他允许你吃糖果和冷饮
The one that lets you have lollies and fizzy drinks
他允许你晚归
he lets you stay up late,
允许你晚上一直看电影
and watch movieslate at night.
丹尼尔，你好吗
Daniel, how are you?
卡斯珀和我是多年的朋友
Casper and I went way back.
我爱你（法语）
I love you
我说的对吗？
Is that right?
是的
Yes!
这是乔治
This is George.
罕见的英国人，本钱(指男性那话儿)雄厚
A very limited English,but a very large penis.
我说的没错吧，乔治
Isn't that right, George?
你说是就是吧
Ok.
我们从Lonely Planet 95年出版的哈瓦那旅行指南说起
Our entire conversation is based on the 1995 "Lonely Planet" guide to Havana
请坐
Sit down.
都是好朋友嘛
Just good friends.
今天有什么安排
So, what's on the agenda today?
没啥，我们想四处逛逛
Not much, we're just wandering around.
嗯，能不能借给我们50块
Um, Could you spare us $50?
凯蒂，他赤裸裸的绝望让你难堪了吗
Does is ever embarrassed you, Candy?...His naked desperation!
裸体，我可以应付
Nakedness, I can deal with!
或者给我们一些迷幻药，我们可以拿去卖吗？
Or give us some ecstasy .we can sell for it?
只怕我作为一名娱乐制药商的
I'm afraid that my days as a manufacturer of ...
日子已经到头了
recreational farmaceuticals has come to an end.
为什么呢？
Why's that?
我现在是有机化学副教授了
I've been made Associate Professor of Organic Chemistry.
-哇呜！恭喜你！-太棒了！
-Wow! Congratulations. -Great.
因此，我要维护我的声誉
So, suddenly I have a reputation to uphold.
那么既然如此，100块可以不？
Well in that case, could we make it a hundred?
我们会还你的！
We'll pay it back!
谢了，卡斯珀
Thanks, Cas.
你没事儿吧？
Everything's alright, isn't it?
只是现金周转问题，七天而已
It's just a cash flow problem.Only 7 days.
你呢，凯蒂
And you, Candy?
这是条通向死亡的新路！
Being one that's so new to the path of the dead!
她很好
She is fine.
当断不断
When you can stop,people don't want to...
必受其乱
... and when you want to stop,You can't!
生命就像筛子
One of life's little riddles!
省省吧，老太太
What Grandma?
你们可以走了
Off you go!
谢谢你，卡斯珀
Thank you, Casper.
你好了吗？
Okay, are you ready?
一,二,三...
One, two, three ...
我像《芝麻街》里的角色一样困惑
I feel like some confused Sesame Street character!
开车
Start the car.
我父母很久以前就对我放任自流了
My own parents had long since cut me adrift
凯蒂的父母，相反地，管教很严
The Wyatts, on the other hand,kept their firm hold on the ropes.
还要土豆吗？
Do you want more potatoes?
我喜欢来这儿，就是为了大饱口福
It was nice to visit places where the fridge was always full.
下次来这儿我要带上盘子
I shall have to bring my plate round when I come here!
我想你会发现那是部分碳水化合物
I think you'll find that's part of the carbohydrate.
你有主意没？
What do you think?
我不知道 我不知道
I don't know.I don't know.
看你怎么做了
See how you go.
担架？
Stretchers?
就是在木架子上铺上帆布
They're like wooden frames you stretch the canvass on.
不管怎样，我觉得很蠢
and anyway, I feel really stupid ...
我大约一个月前做的，我把我们的存款都搭在担架上了
I did about a month ago,and as of tomorrow I'm gonna lose
our deposit on the stretchers.
恕我冒昧地问一句
It is really rude to ask ...
至少我不想令她感到惊讶
but at least I won't surprise her!
下次见你我会还钱
I can give you the money back the next time I see you again.
你能给他打电话，让他等一个星期吗
Can you ring him, and tell him to wait for a week?
上星期我已经很努力地尝试过了
I already tried that pretty much last week.
我给他打电话怎样？
What if I rang him for you?
我没带卡
I haven't got the card with me.
多少钱
How much is it?
150块
150.
不是钱的问题
Mate, the question is not the money.
我非常感激
I really appreciate it.
问题是...我女儿的将来
The question...is the future of my daughter.
她简直妙极了
Mate, she's fantastic!
你该看看她的画作
Should see her paintings!
问题出在你身上
The question is you.
你打算何时有所作为
When are you gonna do something?
我已经有了主意
I've got some ideas.
我给一些热门杂志寄去了我的诗作
I've sent some of my poems into Heat magazine.
-咖啡来了!-牛奶...糖，在那儿!
-Here we are! -Milk...and sugar, There!
-谢谢你，甜心 -谢谢你，伊莱恩
-Thanks babe! -Thanks, Elaine.
你不再是小孩了
You're not a teenager anymore.
你知道这回事，不是吗
You know that, don't you?
是的，我知道，吉姆
Yes, I know that, Jim.
所以我不想你做这事儿
that is why I did'nt want you to do it!
别啊，它很好，很棒
No, it's alright! It's fine!
你瞅瞅!你把它全弄进奶油里去了!
Look at it!You've turned it into butter!
我告诉过你用混的
I told you to keep it on blend!
我用的是搅，因为我在搅奶油
I put it on "Whip", because I'm whipping cream!
但是你一窍不通
Yes, but you don't know how to use it.
好吧，你来弄
Right... You do it!!
-呜!!已经太迟了! -啊!很抱歉!
-Uhh!Well it's too late now! -Ah well!! Excuse me!!
所有设置都是相关的，如果你不熟悉它的操作...
Well all these settings are relative,
and if you're not familiar with the workings of the machine ...
那这儿为啥写着“搅拌”
Then why the fuck does it say "Whip"?
我要给他们做冰激凌
I'll give them ice cream.
别骂骂咧咧的
And please don't swear.
好吧!我本打算给你们做冰激凌，现在只能给你们奶油了
Right!Well, I was going to give you cream,
but I'm going to have to give you Ice Cream.
-一切都顺利吗？ -我们活在希望之中
- Everything okay in there? -Well, we live in hope!
这是个好居所
A good place to live.
去吧!!
Go!!
我不知道这是否？
I wonder if that was it?
是否什么？
If that was what?
我们的弹药（指毒品）耗尽了
The last shot.
我不在乎
I wouldn't care.
这是祖母留下的
It was my Nana's.
我们不会卖任何东西，我们只是将它典当出去
We're going to sell anything.We're only hocking it!
会赎回来的
We'll get it back!
25块
$25.
他不想要这些画
and He doesn't want the paints.
我会回来的
I'll be back!
他说也许我们应该另想办法
He said maybe we could work something out!.
开车
Let's go!
是的，我跟他上床了
Yes, I fucked him!
为了50块
For $50.
我真贱!
I stink!
你没问题吧?
You okay?
我很抱歉
I'm Sorry.
别这样!
Don't be!
这是一个无人知晓的深藏已久的秘密
Here is the deepest secret that nobody knows .
这颗生命之树，它是根之根,是芽之芽
Here is the root of the root,and the bud of the bud...
是天空的天空
and the sky of the sky,in the tree called life .
它高过灵魂之期盼，不能被思想隐藏
which grows higher than soul can hope, or mind can hide .
它是让繁星保持距离的奇迹
and this is the one that is keeping the stars apart.
我把你的心带在身上
I carry your heart.
用我的心将它妥善保藏
I carry it in my heart.
你会嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
我们会成为夫妻
We will be man and wife.
共结连理
One flesh.
你们是否自愿承当婚姻的责任
I will ask them if they freely undertake the obligations of marriage ...
并且确定没有法律障碍
... and to state that there is no legal impediment to the marriage.
你们准备好了吗,完全自愿并且没有任何异议地...
Are you ready,freely and without reservation ...
把自己献给对方而成就一段美满姻缘
to give yourself to eachother... in marriage?
是的，我们准备好了
We are!
你们是否愿意互相敬爱，彼此忠诚
Are you ready for love and honor each other ...
相敬如宾，共度余生
as husband and wife, for the rest of your life?
我们愿意!
-We are! -We are!
凯蒂，丹尼尔
Candice and Dan ...
回来，亲爱的
Come back, love.
啊，好的
Ah, okay.
大家靠近一点，珍妮，气球往下一点
Alright everyone, Close together! Balloons down, Jenny.
大家笑一笑!大喜的日子!
Big smiles, everyone! Happy Day!
一，二...哇靠
One, two... Oh, Shit!
舒曼!
Schumann!
-一，二...三! -好...
-One, two... Three! -Right...
大家不去吃点儿喝点儿？
Alright everyone! Back to our place for a few drinks,and a bite to eat?
很抱歉，我必须走了，我有个约会
I'm sorry, I'm going to have to go,I've got an appointment!
哦，好吧，希望其他人没有约会
Oh! Well, I hope that nobody else has got an appointment!
怀亚特夫人，我可是期待很久了
I'm in for the long hall, Mrs. Wyatt.
很好
Good.
不，我恨拼写
No, I hate spelling!
我也是!最恨拼写和数学!
Yeah, me too! Spelling and maths!
我一直对拼写和数学深恶痛绝
I was always hopeless at spelling and maths.
-我喜欢英文 -英文?
-I like English. -English?
就像故事之类？
Like stories and stuff?
Yeah!
英文和体育!
English and Sport!
那你可不能行差踏错
Well you can't go wrong there.
你可以做体育记者
You can be a Sports journalist.
真的吗
Really?
我一看你就是当体育记者的料
I could see you as a sports journalist.
好嘛，丹尼尔，你真可笑
Well, Dan, you're laughing mate!
帮帮这对小夫妻吧
Financing this love as a married couple.
你已经得到了你最想要的，你为它付出了你的一切
You get the first one under your belt,
you pour everything into it.
毕竟，你要的并没有低于你的最低期望
After that, the minimum equity is what you're after.
你现在负债累累
You get into as much debt as possible.
婚姻可使你更专注一些
It gives you some focus.
我不仅仅在说不动产
I'm not just talking about real estate.
我还在跟你讨论生活的哲学
I'm talking about a philosophy.
不好意思，打扰一下
Would you mind...if you excuse me for a minute?
请便!
No! Sure!!
你和丹去打算哪儿度蜜月?
Where are you and Dan going for the honeymoon?
-需要柠檬水吗? -谢谢!
- More lemonade?  -Yeah, thanks!
你太紧张了!明年升中学了吗?
You're so tight! You're selling next year?
阿波茨路!就在我们附近!
Abbots Road! It's just round the corner from us!
天哪,那会有所不同的，嗯?
Geez, that'll be a change, eh?
耶，我想读州立学校，但是我父母...
Yeah, I'd rather go to a state school,but, it's mom and dad...
珍妮,过来帮我弄三明治
Jenny, could you come and help with sanwiches
我也来帮手,凯珀阿姨
I'll give you a hand too, Auntie Cap!
-咋了? -你们在那儿干嘛?
- What? - What are you doing in there?
没干什么
Doing a shit.
你小子有鬼!
No you're not!
开门
Open the door.
不行!
I can't!
你这贪婪的杂碎
You greedy fuckup!!
结婚是个相当自私的选择
Rather a selfish way to begin a marriage!
真的！全完了！
Really! All done!
蠢货！
Dick!
显然，这是属于瘾君子的周末！
Obviously, it was a big dope weekend!
谁不想在自己的婚礼上放松
You wanna be relaxed at your own wedding.
-对此我很抱歉 -这没什么
-Sorry about that. -That's fine!
我们说到哪儿了？
So where were we?
我说了，你应该尝试...
I was saying, you need to get your t...
你不坐吗？请坐吧！
Do you need a seat? Yeah, sure! Have a seat!
吉姆，你该了解市场
You need to get your toe in the the market, Jim!
你明白我的意思吗？住到远郊，很好！
You know what I'mn saying? Out of suburbs, fine!
两间卧房...
Two bedroom...
你们不需要带花园庭院吗？
...You don't need a garden courtyard, do you?
你竟然在最棒的街区住最差的房子！
You want the worst house, in the best street!
你们需要厨房或者浴室吧...
You don't need a kitchen or bathroom...
再说吧！
Put it in later!
比方说，你要借...
Say for example, you want to borrow ...
400块
400.
或者300
Or 300
你想借钱...你内心争斗...
You do it...You Struggle...
你的明白？
Understand?
丹？
Dan?
丹！
Dan!
丹...
Dan...
醒醒
Wake up.
丹，丹，醒醒
Dan, Dan, wake up.
我惨了
I'm fucked.
他喝了太多的香槟
Too much champagne.
我...我可以肯定
Yeah I'm...I'm sure it's that...
这是个大日子
Well, it is the big day!
我煮点儿咖啡
I'll make some coffee.
他醉了！
He's drunk!
你想和我谈些什么吗？
Is there anything you want to talk to me about?
什么？
What?
发生什么事了？
What's going on?
妈，你知道的！
Mum, you know what's going on!
我们要享受一段美好时光
We are having a lovely time!
我不是那个意思
That's not what I meant.
那么，我就不知道你什么意思了
Well then, I don't know what you mean!
丹咋了？
What's wrong with Dan?
他醉了，妈妈，他没什么
He's just pissed, Mum!He's hopeless!!
对不起
Sorry.
谢谢你们的盛情款待
Thanks for the beautiful reception.
你要知道，那会气死你父亲的
It'd kill your father, you know.
你不认为我们应该戒掉吗
Think we should stop?
-什么？难道我们不够体面吗？-是的，很体面！
-What? Now that we're respectable? -Yeah, I know!
你知道我的意思
You know what I mean.
任何时候你说的“戒”这个词，我都明白
Whenever you say the word.
我们是麦当劳里最酷的人
We are the coolest people in McDonalds!
我们有很多优点
We had a lot going for us.
我们发现了将一切聚合起来的秘诀
We'd found the secret glue that held all things together
在一个没有噪音的
in a perfect place...
完美之地
...where the noise did not intrude.
我们的世界是如此...完整
Our world was...so very complete.
大地
Earth
-嘿，宝贝！-嗨！
-Hey baby! -Hi!
它怎么样？
How was it?
都差不多
About the same.
给你200块
Here's $200.
我大概需要半个钟头
I'm gonna give it half an hour and then I'll split!
耶，我不会太久，家里见
Yeah. I won't be long.I'll meet you at home.
好的，家里见
Ok, I see you there.
好的
OK.
有人说，用不了十年你就会成为一名吸毒者
They say that for every 10 years you've been a junkie ...
你会花七年等待
You will have spent 7 of them...waiting.
一边花同样的时间思考
One way is not bad have as much time to think .
一边忍受着工作的苦闷
on the other, the anxiety was a full time job!
-嘿？-你这个贱人！
- Hey? - You slimey cunt!
-咋了？-你他妈怎么看这事儿？
- What?  - What do you fucking reckon?
我只是稍微快了点儿，啥也没有
I just had a quick little bit! It was nothing!
哪里？
Where?
唔，公园。我遇见安吉的时候
Um, In the park. When I met Ange.
安吉拉和你一起那啥了？
Did Angela do it with you?
没，当然没，我们交易完就离开了
No, of course not!
We left as soon as we did the deal!
他可以体面地回家见他女友.你本来也可以！
Only because he's decent enough to go home to his girlfriend.
Like you should be!
哦，凯蒂！他卖我大麻！为啥他总想着在公共厕所里备受欢迎？
Oh candy! He sold me the dope! Why would he want to have a hit
in the public toilet?
那你他妈也这么想？
Well why the fuck would you?
哇呜！听着，我承认这很蠢！
Oww!Look, I admit it was dumb!
你满意了？
Okay?
我很遗憾！
I'm Sorry!
让我给你尝点儿甜头吧！
Will you let me make you a nice taste!
白痴，我讨厌这样！
I'm getting sick of this, dickhead!
你的问题出在哪儿？
What is your problem?
你就是我的问题！
You are my problem!
你的存在简直是在浪费空间
You are a waste of space.
你找到了自己的人生或其他什么吗？
Are you getting your period or something?
没有，丹！
No, Dan.
我再也没有自己的人生了！
I hardly have my period anymore!
因为我的身体已经沉沦了！
...because my body's all fucked up!
是你把我带进这个该死的梦靥
It's this fucking nightmare you've led me into!
哦，是吗？我有拿枪指着你的头让你吸毒吗？
Oh right! Like I held a gun to your head! Did I? Eh??
我有逼你这么做吗？
Held you down, hit you up, did I?
操你大爷！
Fuck You!
操你妈的，凯蒂！
Fuck you too, Candy!
那好，我操你全家！
Well, Fuck you double then!
丹，你发现没有，我越认真，画得越差
Dan, have you noticed, the more I work, the less I paint?
凯蒂，我不想争吵！
Candy, I don't want a fight! OK?
我就是不明白今晚你是怎么了！我是说...
I just don't see what your problem is tonight! I mean...
我们一起生活！
We've got a life!
这没有什么好坏之分！
It's neither good nor bad! OK?
你知道...你知道我在做什么吗？
Do you know... Do you know what I do?
仔细听着，蠢货！
Listen to this, dick fuck!
我整天都在干嘛？
What do I do all day?
我恨我现在的境况！
I fuck men I hate!
-别这样  -我该怎么办？
-Don't do this. -What are going to do about it?
看这，就靠这个！不是吗？
Look, Okay, that's it! Alright?
没有妓院，没有陪伴！
No more brothels, No more escorts!
-我们正开始崭新的生活！ -你根本不懂
-We're gonna take the time to start a new life!
-You don't understand do you?
这就是我们的新生活，过去的让它过去吧
That's really it this time.That's going away!
或许我想继续
Maybe I want to keep using!
你知道，我讨厌工作，是的，但是
You know, I'm sick of working,yes,but...
假如我要继续吸毒，你会怎么办？
...What if I want to keep using?
What are you gonna do about it?
凯蒂！
Candy!
你怎么不去找个同性恋
Why don't you ring gay blokes?
你开始工作！你去卖自己的屁股！
You start working!You hock your ass!
嘿，你不可以这么做
Hey, you know you can not do that!
你想想，我会...我会得艾滋！
You know, I'll get...I'll get AIDS!
你不会，白痴！
No you won't, you moron!
你可以跟所有人一样用避孕套
You'll make them use condoms,like everybody else!
我不知道怎么办
I wouldn't know what to do.
你是异性恋，对吧？你只要做你擅长的事情就行了
You're heterosexual, right? So you're
just doing what you're good at anyway.
你知道自己在说什么吗？
Did you even hear what you're saying?
让我去干女人，没问题！
Let me fuck women, no problems!
如果我干女人可以来钱，我保证你不用工作
If I can do it with women, I'd make us all the money!
You'd never have to work, I swear!
但是...这些女人不是喜欢肌肉男吗？
But... These women, they want muscle types, don't they?
如果做鸭有市场，我乐意做，但是我不认为有市场
If there was a market out there, I'd do it, but I don't think there is!
而且你要知道，我不可能成为同性恋
And I'd be hopeless with the gay stuff!You know that!
你他妈的真令人难以置信
You're fucking unbeleivable!
开着电视我睡不着
I can't get to sleep with that on.
你能关了它吗？
Can you turn it off?
凯蒂，这的确是部优秀的影片
Candy, it's a really good movie!
我把声音调小一点，可以吗？
I'll turn it down, okay?
不管怎样，半小时就结束了
Anyway, it finishes in half an hour.
去你妈的！
Fuck you!
上床！
Go to bed.
听到没有？
How can you even hear that?
光线干扰到我了！
The light's bugging me!
我无法相信
I can't believe it.
我真他妈难以相信
I can't fucking believe it.
有怎么了？我没发出任何动静
What? I'm not making any noise.
是光！
The light!
有光我睡不着！
The Light's keeping me awake.
好吧，我把光遮起来，行了吗？
OK, look! I'll cover the light!Hmm??
这样光线就没那么强了！
There's more light coming from the workshop than that!
混蛋！
Asshole!
笔！我听见笔划过纸的声音！
The pen!! I can hear the pen scratching on the paper!
这太荒谬了，凯蒂！
How? This is ridiculous, Candy.
你在找借口！
You're just looking for an excuse!
关灯上床！
Turn off the light and come to bed.
我不想再和你讨论这件事
I'm not going to discuss this with you anymore!
关灯！
Turn the light off!
不！我也不想跟你说！
Nope! I'm not even talking to you!
-关上这该死的灯 -啊哈！
-TURN THE FUCKING LIGHT OFF!! -...Aghhh!
我操！
FUCK!!
哦，我天！哦，我的天哪！
Oh my God! Oh my God!
-靠！  -对不起，丹尼！
-Shit. -I'm so sorry, Danny!
-什么东西？-哦，我的天！哦，宝贝！哦，糟糕！
-What the fuck was that? -Oh my God! Oh baby! Oh shit!
天哪，流血了！
Jesus! It's fuckin' blood!
我不是故意伤到你的...
I didn't mean to hurt you...
西瓜，香蕉，你的大巴拉!
Jesus fuckin' shit, alright!.Fuck!
可以用吗啡吗？
Is there any chance for some morphine?
我很疼
I'm in a fair bit of pain.
我不觉得你需要吗啡
I don't think you need any morphine.
我觉得你不太疼
I don't think you're in much pain at all!
值得一试啊！
Oh well, it was worth a try!
打扰了，你不介意我们拿两瓶牛奶吧？
Excuse me, would you mind if we um,
bought a couple of flavoured milks off you?
-拿去吧 -你确定？
-Just take a couple. -You sure?
别担心！
No worries!
-要点这个？-是的
-Want some of this? -Yeah!
-祝你过个愉快的夜晚！-谢谢 -谢谢你
-Have a good night! -Thanks. -Thankyou!
还要吗？
D'you want anymore?
有一阵没那个了
It's been a while.
是啊，有一阵了
Yeah! It's been a while.
伤到你的头，我真的很内疚
I'm sorry I hurt your head.
我会让你好好起来的
I'll get you back!
喂，有人在家吗？
Hello.... Anybody home?
你他妈是谁？
Who the fuck are you?
是我，菲尔
Yeah, it's me! Phil.
菲利普达德利，商业不动产经济
Phillip Dudley,from Commercial Realty.
我之前给你们寄过信
I've written to you lately.
-有什么问题吗？-这个...
-What's the problem? -Well...
我们是想通知你们，嗯...
We've been writing to you about...Um...
我把信..呃..放在..呃..这儿
I've got these..er.. hang on..Er, here they are!
三封信件的复印件，我们最近寄给你的...
Copies of the three letters we've sent you recently...
关于...呃...你们欠下的租金
Relating to the matter of your er,rent in arrears.
我过来确认一下，第三封信是通知你们搬出
I'm here to confirm that the 3rd of these
letters is in actual fact a notice to vacate.
在七天之内
Effective 7 days hence.
我日！
Fuck!
事实上你们收到信已经28天了
Well of course it was...28 days when you received the letter.
现在，我今天来此的初衷...
Now, what I'm actually here for today...
是要指明你们的透支情况
is to point out to you the shortfall owing on the fault of your bond.
假如..你们直到下周三还不能交租
Assuming... you've paid no more rent between now and next wednesday...
我们算过，届时你们将透支..呃..1125元
We've calculated that the shortfall will be er... $1,125.
听着，菲利普...
Listen, Phillip...
...我俩都吸毒！
...we're junkies!
我是个娼妓！
I am a hooker!
他游手好闲!
He's hopeless!
这样一来，事情好像变得复杂了，我们一分钱也没有
Right now, things are very complicated! We haven't got any money.
是的
Right.
但是这很好
But it was good...
当日子变得艰难
Right when times got tough...
还有卡斯珀帮我们
There was always Casper. .
啊，年轻人
Ah, the young ones!
嗨！
Hi!
他就是我们暴风雨中的港湾
Our... port in the storm!
别疯过头了！
Don't get overexcited!
是为我们遮风挡雨的房子
our gingerbread house!
就一次...我来这儿...给你们好东西
For once... Here I come...Bearing Treats!
就是它了？
So is this it?
不是我自夸，我花了一个小时来配药
An honour student didn't show, so I had an idle hour to fill.
你做这个用了一个小时
You made that in an hour?
帕纳丁（一种镇痛药）加吗啡，花了我一小时十分钟
Well... Panadine to morphine,in about an hour and 10!
如果你有扑热息痛
If you get rid of the paracetamol...
你知道怎么做
...do a few things...
15分钟之内连同吗啡一起加进海洛因
...and morphine to heroin in 15 minutes.
谢谢，伙计们
Thankyou, you guys!
重新排列
Rearrange the atoms...
取出一点
...take a bit off...
放进一点
...put a bit on...
二乙酰吗啡
Liquid Diamorphine...
一般被称为海洛因，专业制药级别的，高纯度
Commonly known as heroin,pharmaceutical grade, pure.
我称之为“疯狂耶稣”
I call it "My Yellow Jesus!"
熊爸爸
Papa bear.
熊妈妈
Mama bear.
熊宝宝
Baby bear.
凯蒂说我必须开始尽一份力
It's just that... Candy says I have to start pulling my weight!
耶
Yeah.
你了解同性伴侣吗
What do you know about gay escorts?
同性恋越来越多
Growth market.
介意我问一些技术上的问题吗？
Would you mind if asked you a few technical questions?
我没什么想跟你说的！
There's nothing I'd rather discuss with you!
他们希望你做什么？
What do they expect you to do?
公园里有一大堆同性恋！
Well there's a big down in the park!
你为什么不去研究研究！
Why don't you pop down and do some research!
我是说...
I mean...
如果他们给你钱，他们希望你的阴茎勃起吗？
If they pay you, would they expect you to have a stiffie?
勃起的阴茎会有用的
It Helps!
我不认为我能那样做
I don't think I could manage that.
我只是洗洗手而已
I'm just washing my hands.
那好吧！
Alright!
他会注销他的卡
He'll cancel his cards.
如果我先遇到他,事情就不会像现在这样了.
Not if I get to him first.
罗..罗杰..罗基宝贝！罗杰唐纳德
M. Ro. Roger. Rog. Rogie baby!Roger, Donald.
罗杰唐纳德，在这儿！
R.D. Here it is!
罗杰唐纳德莫伊兰，彼得森区查尔斯街48号
R.D. Moylan，48 Charles Street, Petersham.
他会跟踪电话
He'll trace the call.
这就是发明预付电话的原因
That's why they invented prepaid phones.
啊，嗨，罗杰？
Ah, Hi! Roger?
是罗杰莫伊兰吗？
Is that Roger Moylan?
看，看，这很难...
Yeah, Look! Look, This is hard...
是我偷了你的钱包
I'm the guy who stole your wallet.
不，别挂！我说对不起，行了吧？
我打电话就是为了道歉，我真的很抱歉！
Yep! No, hold on! I'm sorry, okay?
That's why I'm calling! I'm really sorry!
我只是...欠了一些债，我想要一些现金...而且你啥也没有...
I just... I was after some money,
I saw some cash... and you had none...
我想还您钱包！
I want to give your wallet back!
是的，我知道，我很蠢！我只是，只是...
No, I know! I feel so stupid!It's just that I'm...
感到非常孤寂...
I'm so lonely right now...
我没有钱，我来自阿德莱德(澳大利亚南部城市)
I've got no money,I've just come from Adelaide...
我没有朋友...
And I've got no friends...
我看见钱包在座位上，我就拿了，我想都没想！
You know, I saw the wallet on the seat,
and I took it! I wasn't thinking!
我对你的信用卡没有任何兴趣
And I'm not interested in your credit cards.
我只是想做对的事，把钱包还给你
I just want to do the right thing and give it back to you.
啊...那好，不！现在还不是时候，我...
Uhh...  Well, no! I mean now's not a good time, I...
我对整件事有点儿紧张
I'm a little bit nervous about this whole thing anyway!
我们可以...明天早上再碰面吗
Can we just...Let's meet in the morning!
你几点...几点上班？
What...What time do you go to work?
你住在彼得森，对吗？
So you're in Petersham, right?
嗯...那下面有个椭圆形的足球或者别的什么？
Umm... Isn't there a footie oval down there or something?
我们用最简单有效方式见面吧
How about we meet out in front of the greyhound stand?
九点半可以吗？
9:30? Is that good?
那好，我到时会戴蓝色的棒球帽
Well I'll be wearing a blue baseball cap!
注意！听着，这是我的号码！
Look! look, Take my number!
你有笔吗？好的...
You got a pen? Yep, Right...
- 0422 844 881- [这是我家管道工的号码！]
- 0422 844 881 - [That's my Plumber's!]
是的，881
Yes, 881.
好吧，你有移动电话吧，万一...
Well, have you got...a mobile just in case there's a...
是的...是的...嘿，告诉我一件事...
Yeah... Yeah! Hey, Tell me one thing...
你是的证件照怎么这么可爱？
How did you manage to get such a cute photo on your license?
很抱歉！非常抱歉，我扯太远了！
I'm Sorry! Yeah, I'm sorry, I go too far!
好吧，9点半，到时候见
Alright! 9:30 then! I'll see you then!
很好，谢谢你，罗杰，再见
Alright, Thanks Rog! Okay, bye!
丹，想象一下为了人类的福祉而运用你的力量
Imagine if you'd turned your powers
to the benefit of mankind... Dan!
这看起来像我吗？
Does this look like me?
一点儿也不
Not even remotely.
我可以借用一下你的眼镜！
I could use these!
有点像...
And a bit of...
现在如何？
...How about now?
戴眼镜的白种人
Caucasian man with glasses.
棒极了~
Yes!
我觉得自己像人猿泰山
I felt like Tarzan,at fuckin' last!
我得去为“简”（指凯蒂）猎取食物了
I had to hunt down some food for Jane.
我知道我该胆大妄为一回了
I knew it was in my power to do something brave.
是的...
Yeah...
你回办公室后，我们可以谈谈吗？
Can we talk about this when you get back to the office?
20分钟之后...好的，再见！
20 minutes... Okay, bye!
很抱歉！
Sorry about that!
早上好，你好吗？
Good morning,How are you?
很好，你好吗？
Ah, good!How are you?
还好
Good.
我是想核对一下余额
I just uh, wanted to check my
current balance on this please!
好的，输一下你的个人识别号
Okay, I'll just need to get you to
enter in your PIN...
哦，天哪，我..感觉糟透了
Oh God, I'm...terrible with this!
天哪！你有过记不住个人识别号的困扰吗？
God! Do you ever have trouble remembering your PIN?
对于记不住数字的人你确实该感到惊讶
You'd be surprised at the number of
people who forget them.
我知道，所以我进来...
Yeah I know! That's why I came inside...
我在ATM机外面记不住密码，我想...
Because I couldn't remember it
out at the ATM, and I thought...
如果我有身份证，我可以，呃...
You know I could just er..If I had ID?
不！很抱歉，你需要个人识别号来交易
No! I'm sorry, you need your PIN number for all transactions. It's...
这是安全保障之一
It's one of those security things!
是的，当然，当然，我理解
No! Of course, of course!I understand. Um...
你不能通融一下..
So you can't just...
我真的不能！
I really can't!
喂？
Hello?
-莫伊兰先生吗？ -你是？
-Mr. Moylan? -Yes?
-罗杰莫伊兰先生吗？ -怎么？
-Mr. Roger Moylan?  -Yes?
罗杰莫伊兰，我是联邦银行安全部门的伊万道格拉斯
Roger Moylan, This is Ewan Douglasfrom
the Commonwealth Bank Security division...
是的，有事吗？
Yes? Is something the matter?
在过去的24小时我们留意到您信用卡的一些非正常的交易
We've been tracking some unusual activity on
your credit card, in the last 24 hours...
哦，不！
Oh no!
您最后一次使用主卡是在什么时候？
When was the last time you used your Master Card?
听着！我的钱包昨晚被偷了...
Um, look! I think my wallet was stolen last night...
您报失了吗？
Did you report it missing?
我正在打电话报失！
I was just calling now!
但这是我给您打的电话
But I called you.
我是说我正要给你们打电话
Um, I mean I was about to call.
莫伊兰先生，我要核对一下您的详细信息
Sir, Mr. Moylan, I'm going to have to
verify your details for a security check.
可以告诉我您的出生日期吗？
Would you please tell me your
Date of Birth?
嗯...1977年3月13号
Um... 13th of March, 1977.
您母亲的姓氏是？
Mother's Maiden Name?
呃，林奇
Er, Lynch.
您的安全号码？
Number of security?
是个人识别号吗？
Is that like your PIN number?
不一定...但一般都是！
Well, it shouldn't be...but you often find that it is!
嗯...试试3279
Umm...Try... 3279
某些日子，你会忘记所有的事情
It's just one of those days, you know...
where everythings just gone!
常有的事！
It happens all the time!
嗯，听着...我已经取到每日限额
Um, but listen... I've already got my daily limit out from the ATM outside...
但是我需要更多，我想买下一辆老式的梅赛德斯
...But I actually need more, because
I'm trying to buy this beautiful old Mercedes....
奶油色的，你知道的，TLS？
...you know, the cream ones,you know, the TLS?
话说回来，那些人总是要收现金
Anyway, the guy's willing to negotiate for cash...
2247块
...$2247.
天哪，我们成穷光蛋了
God, we're going to be in the poor house!
50分！
...and 50 cents.
千万别对一辆车动感情！
Never get sentimental about a car!
我本来要你查一下这张卡的可用额度...
I might just get you to check the
available credit on this card...
我可以取现吗？
I can get a cash advance, can't I?
凯蒂？凯蒂！
Candy? Candy!
我做到了，我他妈做到了，宝贝！
I did it! I did it! I fucking did it, baby!
我他妈真的做到了！
I fucking did it!
天，你会为此爱死我的！
God, You... are going to fucking LOVE me for this...
7千块！
7 Grand!!
天！你该看看它！我太伟大了，它就像...
Oh god! You should have seen it!
I was fucking great! It was like...
就像那部电影
It was like that movie we saw with that...
天，他叫啥来着，那个我们喜欢的演员？
God, what was his name,that actor we like?
他得到了所有的钱，他简直酷毙了 -丹尼！
...and he gets all that money,and he walks in and he's all coool,
and stuf like that... -Danny!
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
糟糕
Shit.
凯蒂
Candy.
垃圾
Crap.
这不可能..呃..
It couldn't be, uh...
不
No.
我们从没弄破安全套啊！
We never broke a condom.
我早就知道
I'd know.
是我弄伤你头的那晚
It was the night I broke your skull.
太疯狂了
How fucking weird.
一晚就怀上了
One night.
我可以去做人流
I can get an abortion.
不行
No.
不，不行！
No, no way!
可以的
This is good.
这是注定的
It was meant to be.
这正是我们需要的
This is what we need.
我们必须戒毒了
We've got to stop using.
是的
Yeah.
是的，当然
Yeah, of course.
要糖吗？
Sugar?
两勺
Two, please.
我们要告诉所有人
We've got some news everybody...
我们有孩子了
We're having a baby.
啊，亲爱的
Ah, Darling!
凯蒂甜心，太棒了
Candice, Good God.
我们必须明确一些事情
We just wanted you to know that
we've made some decisions. and uh...
我们预留一部分钱出来养孩子
We've been putting some money aside,haven't we?
我们要离开这个"仓库"
We're going to get out of that
whole warehouse environment.
住进更适合居住的房子
...and live in a proper house.
是的，我们要在一个真正的“家”中
Yeah! We really want to raise our child in the....
...将孩子养大
...in a proper home.
你告诉你的父母了吗？
Have you told your parents?
没有
No.
第一天
Day 1
我们知道我们要做什么
We knew what we had to do.
有很多计划搁浅
It takes alot of planning to stop.
上天保佑！我们一定可以做到，凯蒂！
Lucky at last!We can really do this, Candy.
虽然会很艰难，但是...
It's going to be hard, but...
就像一座桥
I'm sure it's like a bridge...
只要我们走过它，一切都会好起来
And once we cross it,everything will be okay.
你可以继续画画了...
You can get back into your painting again...
也许我们该搬到乡下去...
Maybe we'll move to the country...
种一点蔬菜...
Grow some veggies...
养几只鸡...
Feed the chickens...
我们应该搬到泰国...
We could go live in Thailand...
泰国很好，只要我们不吸毒的话
Thailand would be great,if we didn't use.
或者去喜马拉雅山
Or the Himalayas.
我们将坐上独木舟
We'll go canoeing...
在白色的浪花上漂流
A bit of white water rafting...
积极健康，甜美入睡
Get healthy, sleep well...
不用再受毒品的控制
...not have drugs in our system.
那样该有多好？
How good would that be?
我们必须戒毒
We really have to do this.
我们这次一定要做到
We have to do it this time.
是的，我们会的
Yeah, we will.
我们
We are.
我们正在努力
We're really fuckin' doing it!
第二天
Day 2
第四天
Day 4
我受不了了
I can't do it.
我忍不住了
嘿！回床上来！
Hey!Come back to bed.
你会着凉的
Alright? You'll catch a cold.
卡斯珀，是我，凯蒂
Casper, It's Candy.
你拿到货马上给我电话
Ring me as soon as you get this.
我们打过你手机
We've tried your mobile.
我知道我说过一旦我们要货你就不理我们但是...
I know we said to ignore us while we did this, but...
三天了...
3 days...
...我们已经很出色了，但是我们现在感觉不是很好
...we did pretty well, but we're not feeling so great now.
我们现在很需要你
We don't want you to ignore us now.
你在吗？
Are you there?
在就说话
Pick up if you're there.
说话呀！
Pick up!
好吧，你不在
Okay, you're not there.
给我们电话
Call us!!
妈的！妈的！
Shit! Shit!
Shit! Shit! Shit!
科杰克吗？我是凯蒂啊！
Kojak? It's Candy!
嗯...妈的，很不好
Um... Shit, not so good.
我很痛苦，我的意思是
I'm really sick. I mean...
我们需要信誉
We just need credit.
呃...我会去工作，之后我会还钱的
Uh... I can work a shift,and then I can pay you back.
是的，我可以连那些一起还了
Yeah, well if I work a shift,then I can pay that too.
我难受成这样根本不能工作
I can't work when I'm this sick!
好的，再见
Ok, bye.
狗日的！
Fucking cunt!!
凯蒂
Candy.
-凯蒂  -哦，天哪
-Candy. -Oh God!
接电话
Answer!Answer, please!
他正要接电话
He was just about to answer!
-给我电话  -我要用电话！
-Give me the phone.-I want the fucking phone!
别拿我的电话，不行，不可以！
Don't fucking take it away from me!No! No!!
-我们可以做到的   -不，滚开！不！！！
-We can do it. -No! Get away!! Nooooo!!
凯蒂，你在流血
Candy, you're bleeding.
你怎么会流血？
Why are you bleeding?
羊水破了，她的宫颈扩张了
The water has broken.Her cervix has dilated.
这是我们不愿意看到的
This is what we didn't want to happen.
我们都知道这是无法避免的流产
We call this an inevitable miscarriage.
我们尽力了
There's no going back.
当我努力向凯蒂解释的时候，她正不得不经受...分娩的痛苦
As I was explaining to Candy,she's going to
have to go through a kind of... labour!
我不知道那持续了多久，你必须怀孕过才知道那个过程
I don't know however long that takes, you need to know that at this state of the pregnancy...
孩子没能够活下来
...the baby is not going to survive.
真对不起
I'm Sorry.
给我哌替啶（一种人工合成的镇痛和催眠药）
Give me pethidine!
我需要哌替啶！
I want pethidine!
你不想给她哌替啶吗？
Will you give her the fucking pethidine, or what?
她实在是太痛苦了，难道你没看见？
She's fucking in pain,can't you see this?
就这样！凯蒂，用力！
That's it! Candy, push!
快出来了，用力，对了！！
Almost there! Push! That's it!!
我可以抱抱吗？
Can I hold it?
医生，他的腿动了
Doctor, its leg moved.
只是痉挛而已
It's just a spasm.
他明明动了！
It moved!
就是痉挛！
It's just a spasm.
地狱
Hell
-你赚了多少钱？ -50
-How much did you get?  -50.
那家伙又来了
That guy is still back there.
-也许你会卖一点，会吗？ -好吧
-Maybe you'll sell some. Yeah? -Alright.
我们所做的一切
Everything we ever did...
都怀着美好的愿望
we did with the best of intentions...
但是..年复一年，事与愿违！
But.. events tumble!and the years pile up.
对一个瘾君子来说，世界是扑朔迷离的
The world is very bewildering to a junkie.
耶，我们都很棒
Yeah, we're all good!
-纯度不够  -靠！
-Well... Tastes bad. -Fuck!
开始吧
Here you go.
你察觉到什么了吗？
Do you feel anything?
没啊
No.
-妈的！ -我靠！
-Shit!  -Shit!
你仍然坚持思想的转变
and still... you cling to the concept of change.
嘿，舒曼
Hey, Schumann...
我们正打算搬到乡下住一阵
...we are thinking of moving up the country for a while.
试试美沙酮(一种镇痛药)
Give methadone a try.
这东西有什么不同？
What the fuck difference would it make?
可以当空气清新剂
The air's cleaner, for one.
这是厨房
It's a kitchen.
有点暗，不是吗？
It's a bit dark, isn't it?
是的
Yeah.
是的，我们可以..
Yeah, we Could um...
打一个洞..开个天窗
knock out a hole...and put a skylight.
我爱你
I love you.
有冷冻青豆吗？
Any frozen peas?
没
No.
我找到一个，在那儿
I got one! There he is!
一直是涡轮霜冻
It was all the way down in the turbo frost.
你早上竟然没有准备
I can not believe you didn't do this, this morning.
他们啥时候到？
What time are they coming?
日了！！
Fuck!!
生产日期是多少？
What's the date?
哦，不，过期一个月了
Oh no, this expired a month ago.
你自己看，难闻死了！
Look at that! It smells bad!
-整个厨房都臭了！-难道不是吗？
-That's got that kind of chicken smell!
-Yeah it does，doesn't it!
别担心，亲爱的，我们有很多东西可以用来调味
Not to worry, we'll just baste it in lots of stuff!
Like uh...
比如薄荷叶、月桂叶什么的？
Basil, uh... honey?Bayleaves or something?
橱柜里有什么？
What's in the cupboard?
你用什么烤肉呢？
What do you put on a roast?
你们到这儿花了多长时间？
How long did it take you to get out here?
大概1小时40分钟？亲爱的？
Oh, About an hour and 40 minutes? Dear?
是的，大约40，还是45分钟？
Yeah, about... 40? 45?
不堵车吗?
Much traffic?
不会，一路畅通
No, pretty good run really.
无可挑剔
Can't complain.
这儿太美了，开车是种享受
It's so beautiful here,
the drive down was so beautiful.
是啊，这是乡村
Yeah, it's... Countryside.
找工作有着落了吗？
Had any news on the job front?
额..还行吧..这儿的岗位不是很多，我们靠救济金还过得去
Um... Well it's pretty... There's not much work around here.
We're getting by on the dole.
那么，看来我要找份工作贴补家用了
Well, apparently I might be able to
get some work hay bailing.
贴补家用？
Hay bailing?
-哦！辛苦工作，勉强糊口？-是的
-Ooooh! Tough work, hay bailing!-Yeah.
既然这样，我帮忙做饭吧
So! What can I do in the kitchen?
不需要，真的，我能行！
Nothing mum, really! It's fine!
废话，一定有什么我能帮忙的
Nonsense, there must be something I can do to help.
我自己就能搞定
Everything's under control.
炉子烧开了
The oven's heating up.
我们有些落伍了
We're running a bit behind.
别担心，伙计
No worries, mate.
这真是难以置信，你煞费苦心就是为了请我们到这儿来
Oh This is unbelievable.You go to all this trouble
to invite us up here...
而且你竟然不能按时准备一餐便饭
...and you can't even manage the simple decency of getting the meal together on time!
别管我，妈
Get off my case, mum!
食物还在其次
Is not food that's even the issue here.
问题是你的态度
It's your attitude!
好吧，我们都冷静，午饭不到一小时就好了
Okay, let's just calm down. Lunch will be ready
in less than an hour.
谁想来点儿酒？
Who wants some wine?
那鸡肉像石头！
That chicken is rock solid!
我们午夜前不打算吃东西
We're not going to be eating before midnight.
蔬菜在哪儿呢？
And where are the vegetables?
嘿，嘿，大家都静一静，亲爱的
Hey hey, Let's all calm down, honey.
你在想什么？
What do you think is about?
周日午餐，本来很简单的一件事
Sunday Lunch.It's a pretty simple thing.
但是你俩一掺和，就没简单的事
But with you two, there's no such thing as simple.
毒品！
The drugs!
你们就知道吸毒！
The drugs always come first.
不，不是那样的
Hey no, that is not true.
我们现在已经做的很好了
We're doing really well now.
你知道什么
Do you have any idea...
你对我的家庭都做过什么？
...what you have done to my family?
对我呢？
To me?
那个美丽的女孩怎么啦？
What happened to that beautiful girl?
怎么了？
What happened?
难道你看不见？
Can't you see?
难道你不明白？
Don't you understand?
我六岁起就攥紧了拳头
I have been clutching my fucking fists
since I was 6 years old.
看看我的拳头，仔细看看
Look at my fucking fists!
Look at them!
看看他们，你这烂货
Look at them, you fucking bitch!
难道你不明白
Don't you understand?
我明白！我会握紧我的手！
No! I gotta clench my hands!
我会握紧我的手不放松
I gotta clench my hands! I can't relax.
亲爱的，亲爱的，快看！这是个大动作！
Darling, darling! Look!It's been a big move.
这是不平凡的一年
It's been a big year.
有很多变化
There's been lots of changes.
你们失去了一个孩子
C'mon, you've lost a child.
但是你们的生命连在一起，我可以看到
But you ARE getting your lives together.I can see that!
去吧
Just go.
滚！
Fuck off.
忘记午餐的事吧
Forget lunch.
可以吗？
Can we?
可以取消午餐吗？
Can we cancel the lunch?
我们可以另外挑个好日子
Maybe we can just make this another day.
今天不行，我很抱歉
Today is just a bad day.I'm sorry.
我好怕
I'm scared.
没什么可怕的
There's nothing to be scared of.
你觉得我们结束了吗？
D'you think we're going to end?
-我们永远不会结束  -会的
-We'll never end. -It'll end.
这不管用
It's not gonna work.
是流感疫苗吗？
Is that the flu vaccine?
是药
It's medicine.
它指引我们免于诱惑
It's leading us not into temptation.
嘿，凯蒂，看看这个
Hey Candy, check out this.
招泥水工
Brickie's labourer.
-我要打个电话  -打吧
-I'll give it a call, eh. -Why don't you do that.
-嗨 -嘿
-Hi.-Hey!
这是保罗,他住在这条路的上方
This is Paul. He lives up the road.
你好！
Good day.
他有些家庭自制好东西
He's got some good home grow.
太好了，我能多弄一些吗？
Great.Can I get some more?
嗯，已经没有了
Um... There is none left.
那我要一杯啤酒
Then I'll grab a beer.
也没有了
There's none of that either.
我要出去爽一下
I'm gonna go and get some more pot.
呃..我们不吃晚餐了吗？
Uh.. We gonna grab some dinner,or What?
不，你吃！我不用
No, you eat! I'll be fine.
你需要钱吗？我结工资了
You want some money? I got paid.
-不 - 没关系的，伙计
-No. -No, it's okay mate.
你们去哪儿了？
Where were you?
难道你不打算说几句难听的吗？
Don't you fuck this one with your negative comments.
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
回到我的艺术之中
Going back to my art.
难道这对你有什么意义吗？
Does not mean anything to you?
你和那家伙上床了吗？
Have you been fucking that guy?
你在胡说八道
You do not know what you're talking about.
你整个晚上都去哪儿了？
Where have you been all night?
远离你
Away from you.
你跟他上床了，对不对？
You fucked him, didn't you?
首先...
Firstly...
你在胡说八道
...You do not know what you're talking about.
其次...
Secondly...
我讨厌你的声音
...I hate the sound of your voice.
第三...
Thirdly...
你他妈给我滚蛋
...Why don't you just fuck off?
我是认真的
I mean, really!
滚你妈的蛋!
Fuck off!
醒醒，醒醒
Wakey wakey.Hands off snakey!
那该死的东西是啥
What the fuck is that?
如你所见，你认为是啥？
A statement of fact.What do you think it is?
关你妈什么事？
And what's this with your mother anyway?
如果不是她
Well if it's not her...
那么你
...Then you.
很好
Great.
好吧..你
Okay...You.
你自作聪明，其实是个疯子！
You think you're so smart,but youre just fuckin' mad!
说得好，凯蒂
That's really good, Candy.
说得好，很高兴你这么想
That's good, glad you think that.
你是个混蛋诗人！
Your a fuckin' poet!
曾经，有一对男女名叫丹和凯蒂
Once upon a time, there was a Candy and Dan...
那年一切都很火热
Things were very hot that year...
所有的蜡烛都在树上融化
All the wax was melting on the trees...
他在阳台上蠕动，到处攀爬，为她做任何事
He would crawl on balconies, climb everywhere. Do anything for her...
我的丹尼男孩
My Danny boy.
成千上万的鸟儿，最小的鸟儿装点着她的秀发
Thousands of birds. Thetiniest birds adorned her hair...
一切都是金色的
Everything was golden...
一天晚上，欲火点燃了绣床
One night the bed caught fire...
他风度翩翩，坏得恰到好处
He was handsome, and a very good criminal...
我们住在阳光和巧克力宫殿里
We lived on sunlight and chocolate bars...
午后纵情狂欢
It was the afternoon of extravagant delight...
丹尼，铤而走险的战士
Danny, the Daredevil...
凯蒂为你祈祷
Candy the blessing...
那天的余晖鲨鱼般巡游
The day's last rays of sunshine cruise like sharks....
这次，我要试试你的办法
"I wanna try it your way this time!"
你如此迅速地进入我的生命，并且我喜欢
You came into my life really fast, and I liked it.
我们在欢愉的泥泞中碾得粉碎
We squelched in the mud of our joy.
我双腿潮湿，屈服于你
I was wet thighed with the surrender...
万物之中有条鸿沟
Then there was a gap in things...
整个大地都倾斜了
And the whole earth tilted...
这就是我们追随的
This is the business.This is what we're after.
你在我体内，伴着夜晚降临
With you inside me...Comes the night...、
难再入睡
... never again sleep ...
水池中的怪物
... a monster in the pool ...
黑暗本质的一部分，飞翔
... Part of the black nature, to board ...
鸡和奔跑的青豆
... chickens and runnerbeans ...
我所看到的地方
... everywhere I looked ...
有时我恨你
... sometimes I hate you ...
星期五
... Friday ...
那并非我所指
... I didn't mean that ...
暴风雨..年复一年..有时我恨你
storm ... years ...... sometimes I hate you ...
床边的一盆花
... a box of flowers by the bed...
我一时失手
... I broke your head ...
打破了你的头
... from the back of the bed ...
孩子死于清晨
... the baby died in the morning ...
我给他起了个名字
... I gave him a name ...
他的名字叫托马斯
... His name was Thomas ...
可怜的小家伙
...Poor little guy...
他的心像魔法鼓般跳动
... his heart poundslike a voodoo drum ...
我的名字叫丹尼尔，我是个瘾君子，我今天很干净，但不会长久
My name is Daniel, I'm an addict.I'm clean today, but not for much longer.
滚
Get out.
我想我应该那样做
I suppose I should do just that.
我在卡斯珀家
I am in my house Casper.
答应我你会停下来
Promise me you'll stop.
答应我你在我之前会停下
Promise me you'll stop before me.
我是吉姆怀亚特，可以找丹接电话吗？
can I talk to Dan Cutter,Please? It's Jim Wyatt here.
吉姆，是我
Yeah Jim, it's me.
嗨！凯蒂住院了
Hi! Candy's in the hospital.
什么？
What?
她有点精神衰弱
She's suffered a bit of a nervous breakdown.
结局很有趣，是吗？
It's funny where it all ends up ，isn't it?
凯蒂
Candy.
你没事儿吧？
You okay?
我真被你吓到了
I was so frightened.
对不起
Sorry.
我不知道都发生什么了
I didn't really understand what was happening.
凯蒂？
Candy?
一切都死亡了
Everything's dead.
一切都变成蓝色的了
Everything's turning blue.
这很难承受
It's hard through all this you know.
我不在乎你曾经怎样虚度
I don't care how wrong you've
been living about your years.
我只在乎我的女儿
I care about my daughter.
什么？
What?
不管你能做什么，不管她要什么
Whatever you're capable of...
whatever she needs...
走吧，我们带你回家
Come on, we'll take you home.
让他走
Let him go.
就那样
And that was it...
一切都随风消散
That was all that was scattered to the winds...
卡斯珀消失了
Casper was gone...
舒曼消失了
Schumann was lost...
凯蒂没有好转
Candy was off getting better...
海岸...
The coast...
改过迁善
Rehab...
而我...
And I...Was...
我只是...
I was just...
清洗者，丹
The washer, Dan.
世界冠军级的清洗者
World Championship washer.
有一天，你会为澳大利亚清洗
One day, you'll wash for Australia.
这个世界充满了奇思妙想
The world was full of startling new concepts.
我无法思考，无法呼吸
I couldn't think.I couldn't breathe.
我在等她回来
I was waiting for her to come back.
因为她是我的一切
Because she was everything.
她是我的一切
She was everything to me.
嘿，丹，有人找你
Hey Dan, you have a visitor.
有人找
Visit.
跟她说我不在
Just Tell her I'm not here.
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
告诉她我不在！
Tell her I knocked off.
你的朋友来了，快出来吧
Your friend is right here, just come.
-你好 -嘿！
-G'day. -Hey!
我还以为你明天才来
I thought it was tomorrow.
我等不急了
I couldn't wait.
还好吗
Is that okay?
挺好的
Yeah! No, it's good!
你真漂亮
It's just!You look so beautiful.
乡下的空气养人
It's all that country air.
我一小时后收工
So I finish in an hour.
丹
Dan.
丹，嘿，嘿！
Dan. Hey!Hey!
丹尼，丹尼！嘿！
Danny, Danny! Hey!
没关系的，嘿！
It's Okay.Hey!
嘿，没关系的，我来了
Hey, It's Okay,I'm here now.
我们没有可能了
There's no going back.
如果你得以解脱
If you're given a reprieve...
你为何不去想想
I think it is good to remember...
想想那孩子有多瘦小
...just how thin it is.
剧终